kidzworld.com 2016-06-08

# Privacy Policy | Safe Website For kids - Kidzworld

Established in 2001, Kidzworld is the **_first[safe social network for kids](http://safe.kidzworld.com/)_**. We have developed this policy statement to reflect our **commitment to[kids safety](http://safe.kidzworld.com/), security and privacy**. [Kidzworld](http://www.kidzworld.com/) users have access to the safest kids social network through the website and iPhone App. However, we do try to educate them to be aware of what they are doing everywhere online and to take appropriate steps to ensure their online safety.

We have a sophisticated and highly confidential moderations and behavior management system that protects our users from unwanted and inappropriate conversations, bullying, swearing and sexually inappropriate language. Each user is confidentially profiled based on a sophisticated algorithm. We believe that this software provides our users of all ages with the safest social network environment available. The software platform is also backed up by our admin team, staff moderators and volunteer Jr Mods (long time active reliable users). 

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

Kidzworld is a leading **_safe social network for kids_**. It was established in 2001, by Allen W. Achilles as a direct result of his concern for the online safety and security of his own children. Since that time, he has been a tireless advocate for the **safety and security of kids online**. COPPA (Childrenís Online Privacy Protection Act) became effective on April 21, 2000. The regulations apply to the online collection of personal information from children in the US who are 12 years and younger. The Act spells out what website operators, need to include in their privacy policy, when and how to seek verifiable consent from a parent and what responsibilities website operators have to protect and secure childrenís privacy and safety online.

COPPA applies to individual identifiable information about a child (12 or younger) that is collected online, such as full name, home address, email address, telephone number or any other information that would allow someone to identify or contact a kid. The Act also applies to other types of information, such as hobbies, interests and user information gathered through the use of cookies and other methods of tracking, when they are tied to individually identifiable information. Kidzworld does not use cookies to track user behaviour, interests or hobbies.

Kidzworld and founder Allen Achilles are tireless advocates of Internet safety and privacy. As the only **_fully moderated kids social network_** , we take extraordinary measures to ensure the privacy and safety of our kids.

## Kidzworld User Registration and Membership

Registration requires users to create an anonymous identity that does not include their full name. They provide limited contact information: first name, last initial, email address, age, gender, and country, state/province. The email address is only used to contact users to confirm their registration and at other times when necessary. For users 12 and under we collect their date of birth, location, gender and parent/guardians email address. Kidzworld does not collect personally indentifiable information from any user who is 12 or younger. **Parents/guardians** receives a confirmation email to which they must respond in order to activate the childís account. Parent email addresses are retained in our database for future contact. Accounts not activated within 21 days are deleted from our database. Under no circumstances do we market products or offerings from third parties to our users by email. 

We do not disclose the users personal information to anyone, at any time except by subpoena from authorities. However, in the event of the sale or merger of the company; Kidzworld.com, Inc., the personal information collected by Kidzworld about itsí user in the normal course of its business will be shared with the partner company or successor company upon completion of the subject acquisition or merger. Parents or guardians can review their childís personal information once we receive verifiable identification. Verifiable consent can be given by one of the following methods: following the link provided in the confirmation email, provide a signed form via postal mail or facsimile or even giving us a call. Upon request, parents may delete or prohibit the further collection of their child's personal information by contacting us at **privacy@kidzworld.com**.

Another way that **Kidzworld** accesses information about users is through IP addresses. An IP address is unique to the userís computer, and is used to identify and collect broad demographic information (like age, gender, regional information and generic interests). As a safe social network for kids, tools such as these can be used positively and in the interest of protecting the privacy and safety of all kids online.

Kidzworld also employs a help form for kids to request information, products and services. We collect kidís unique identifiers (their Kidzworld on-screen name) to fulfill these requests, however, the information is not retained. 

Kidzworld hosts regular contests on its desktop wesbite only, in which we ask kids for contact information (like their e-mail address). This information is solely used to contact winners. Contact information collected for contests is deleted once winners have been confirmed. Participation in contests is open to all kids, registered or not. 

## Rules of Conduct and Terms of Use

You have a nonexclusive, limited, revocable license to use the app while you are in compliance with this Agreement. You agree to abide by certain rules of conduct and other rules prohibiting illegal and other practices that we deem harmful. These rules apply to all Users, including Visitors, Parents, and Children. We reserve the right to investigate and take appropriate legal action against anyone who, in our sole discretion, violates any of these terms, including without limitation, removing the offending communication from the App and terminating the Membership of such violators and others acting in concert.

## The KW Zone - Safe Social Networking at Kidzworld

In the member only KW Zone kids can create an online profile where they can design backgrounds, upload pictures and videos, make friends and interact with other kids worldwide. All direct user interaction is fully moderated using the sophisticated computer technology and real live people. Users are cautioned that anything they upload (and is subsequently approved) may be viewable by all users on the website. We recommended that the kids only upload images and information that they are willing to share with others. For added security, online search spiders are blocked from accessing any part of the members only KW Zone.

## Safety Partnerships

## Chat Rooms

Kidzworlds chat rooms are open 24/7 and only accessible to our registered users. We make our users aware that postings and conversations in these areas becomes public information. Users are not allowed to disclose any personally identifiable information. Their anonymous Kidzworld username is their only identity at Kidzworld, and is how users are known on the site. For added security, online search spiders are blocked from accessing any part of the members only KW Zone including the chat room.

## Kidzworld Forums

Kidzworlds **safe and secure** forums are moderated at all times by our moderation and behavioural analysis platform as well as our experienced Kidzworld staff to ensure that the kids do not divulge personal information. Kids who tries to reveal, or ask for, personal information will be blocked from posting in the forums for a period of time. If problems continue their IP address may be permanently blocked and future access denied to the website from that IP address.

## Photo Uploads

Users are allowed to upload socially appropriate photos of themselves, their friends, and other subjects of interest. For safety and security reasons all meta data is removed from all photos prior to being published on the site. All 12 and under US users obtain parent/guardian consent during the registration process in order to upload personal photos.

## Private Messaging

Registered users are able to interact with each other privately using our proprietary and **fully moderated messaging system**. Users interaction is analyzed to ensure that users do not receive inappropriate and unwanted advances, sexually explicit conversation, as well as bullying.

## E-cards

Kidzworld's desktop site offers numerous public domain e-cards for kids to send to family and friends. To send an e-card, kids must know the email address of the person that they are sending to. Thus, it can be assumed that they already know this person in real life. The email is sent from a kidzworld corporate email address NOT the senders email address. Information entered in the e-card is used solely for the purpose of sending the e-card. It is not stored or retained by Kidzworld.

## Outbound Links

Our site contains links to other sites. Although Kidzworld is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other sites, we screen all sites accessible from Kidzworld, as a **[safe social network for kids](http://safe.kidzworld.com/)** , to ensure that they comply with our standards. When a user clicks on an outbound link, they are first directed to a page informing them that they are about to leave Kidzworld.

### Email communications

Kidzworld communicates occasionally with our users by email. Users can opt-out of receiving communications from us in their account settings and in the footer of all emails sent.

### Advertising

Advertising on Kidzworld in the United States is primarily provided through TotallyKidz, which is part of TotallyHer Media, a division of Evolve Media using the Doubleclick for Publishers ad serving platform. Information about visitors to Kidzworld, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not a users name, address, or other personal information), is used to control the delivery of ads on this site. 

We also use third-party advertising networks to serve ads to all visitors. These companies may use information (excluding name, address email address or telephone number) about users visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to them. This functionality is disabled for all US users who are 12 or younger. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

### Third Party Cookies

In the course of serving advertising, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. This does not have any impact on the safety on the website. Users may disable cookies via their browser or [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) for more info on how to do this.

### Security

Kidzworld is a **_safe social network for kids_**. It has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Passwords and personal information is collected and stored on our secure servers. Paper records of data and financial transactions are stored in a locked facility. Information will only be divulged to law enforcement agencies upon subpoena. However, in the event of the sale or merger of Kidzworld.com, Inc., the personal information collected by Kidzworld about itsí user in the normal course of its business will be shared with the partner company or successor company upon completion of the subject acquisition or merger. 

### Contacting Us and Account Cancellation

If you wish to cancel your account or have any questions or comments about our privacy statement, our practices or your dealings with Kidzworld, you can contact us at **privacy@kidzworld.com** , or by snail mail at:

 **Kidzworld.com, Inc.  
Suite 202, 1937 W 4th Ave  
Vancouver, BC  
Canada , V6J 1M7**

**General:** 1-604-688-2010; **Fax:** 1-604-688-2015
